以下内容提供
the following content is provided under
CreativeCommons许可您的支持
a Creative Commons license your support
将帮助MITOpenCourseWare继续
will help MIT OpenCourseWare continue to
提供高质量的教育资源
offer high quality educational resources
免费
for free
捐款或查看额外的捐款
to make a donation or to view additional
数百个麻省理工学院课程的材料
materials from hundreds of MIT courses
访问位于ocw.mit.edu的麻省理工学院开放式课件
visit MIT opencourseware at ocw.mit.edu
所以最后一次是正交矩阵Q.
so last time was orthogonal matrices Q
而这一次是对称矩阵S左右
and this time is symmetric matrices s so
我们真的在谈论最好的
we're really talking about the best
所有的矩阵我都会从任何开始
matrices of all well I'll start with any
方阵和关于特征向量
square matrix and about eigenvectors but
你已经听说过特征向量
you've heard of eigenvectors more than
不止一次超过两倍以上
more than once more than twice more than
十次可能还好，所以特征向量
ten times probably okay so eigenvectors
然后让我们确定我们知道为什么
and then let's be sure we know why
它们很有用，可能会计算一个或
they're useful and maybe compute one or
两个但我们将转向对称
two but then we'll move to symmetric
矩阵和什么特别之处那些
matrices and what is special about those
然后更特别，更多
and then even more special and more
重要的是肯定的
important will be positive definite
对称矩阵，所以当我说
symmetric matrices so that when I say
肯定的我的意思是对称的
positive definite I mean symmetric so
从下一个开始然后来了
start with a next comes s then come the
特殊的对称矩阵
special s special symmetric matrices
有这个额外的肯定
that have this extra positive definite
属性好，所以从这样开始
property ok so start with a so an
特征向量，如果我乘以x得到我
eigenvector if i multiply a by x I get
一些矢量，有时候如果X是
some vector and sometimes if X is
特别选择好的斧头出来了
especially chosen well ax comes out in
与Xax相同的方向出来了
the same direction as X ax comes out
有些数倍X所以有
some number times X so there are
通常会有N乘n
normally there would be for an N by n
矩阵所以让我们说a是n乘n
matrix so let's let's say an a is n by n
今天
today
通常，如果我们生活在那里
normally if we're if we live right there
将是n个不同的独立向量
will be n different independent vectors
具有这种特殊性的XAugen载体
X Augen vectors that have this special
属性，我们可以手动计算它们
property and we can compute them by hand
如果n是2或3，但大多数是
if n is 2 or 3 to mostly but the
在X的计算和拉姆达等等
computation of the X's and the lambda so
这是因为我等于1到n
this is this is for I equal 1 up to n if
我用这种数学速记表示我
I use this sort of math shorthand that I
我和其中几乎总是有这些
have n of these almost always and my
第一个问题是他们有什么好处
first question is what are they good for
那么为什么选择课程呢？
well why why do just course after course
介绍了特征向量，并向我介绍了
introduced eigenvectors and to me the
通过查看a看到关键属性
key property is seen by looking at a
平方所以让我看看这样的平方
squared so let me look at a squared so
它是另一个N乘n矩阵，我们会
it's another N by n matrix and we would
问我们认识这些家伙
ask suppose we know these guys
假设我们发现了那些东西
suppose we found those somehow what
关于平方是X的特征向量
about a squared is X an eigen vector of
找平方也很方便
a squared also well the way to find out
是乘以X的平方并看到
is to multiply a squared by X and see
发生什么事，你看到了什么事情
what happens do you see what's going to
发生在这里这是一个时代的斧头
happen here this is a times ax which is
一次斧头是lambdaX，现在是什么
a times ax is lambda X and and now what
我现在该怎么办，因为我在拍摄
what do I do now because I'm shooting
对于答案，是x是特征向量
for the answer yes x is an eigenvector
平方也是如此，我该怎么做
of a squared also so what do I do that
lambda只是一个数字的数字
number that lambda is just a number
这就是我可以把它放在任何地方，我喜欢，所以我
that's I can put it anywhere I like so I
可以把它拿出来然后我有一个X.
can put it out front and then I have a X
这是lambdaX，谢谢我
which is lambda X thanks so I have
另一个lambdaX和lambda平方X一样
another lambda X so as lambda squared X
所以我这里学到的关键的东西
so I learned the crucial thing here that
X也是我
X is also an I
a平方矢量和特征值
vector of a-squared and the eigenvalue
是lambda平方，当然我可以
is lambda squared and of course I can
继续这么做到最后X是lambda
keep going so a to the end X is lambda
到最后X我们找到了正确的
to the end X we have found the right
该特定矩阵的向量a
vectors for that particular matrix a
怎么样的反X呢？
what about a inverse X that will be if
lambdaX上的一切都很好
everything is good one over lambda X
好吧是啊所以我随时写了一遍
well yeah so anytime I write 1 over
lambda我的脑子里说你要做的
lambda my mind says what you've got to
喜欢对特殊内容做一些评论
like make some comment on the special
情况下它不工作，这是耶
case where it doesn't work which is yeah
如果lambda不是0，那我就是lambda
if lambda is not 0 I'm golden if lambda
是0它看起来不太好但是它是什么
is 0 it doesn't look good and but what's
如果lambda为0，则发生嘿
happening if lambda is 0 hey doesn't
如果lambda为0，甚至有一个逆
even have an inverse if lambda was 0
这可能不是没有规则反对
which it could be no no no rule against
如果lambda为0，那么就会说a
it if lambda was 0 this would say a
特征向量的时间是0倍
times the eigenvector is 0 times the
特征向量，这样就可以告诉我
eigenvector so that would tell me that
特征向量在零空间中
the eigenvector is in the null space it
会告诉我矩阵a不是
would tell me that the matrix a isn't
可逆的它采取了一些向量X
invertible it's taking some vector X to
0等所以一切都点击这个
0 and so so the everything clicks this
它应该工作，如果我们有的话
works when it should work and if we have
其他字体矩阵的任何功能我们
other font any function of the matrix we
可以定义矩阵的指数
could define the exponential of a matrix
18:03会这样做让我们放手吧
18:03 would do that let's just let's
把它写下来好像我们知道它是什么
just write it down as if we know what it
意味着它具有相同的特征
means it does it have the same eigen
矢量很好肯定因为e到了T.
vector well sure because e to the a T
如果我看到矩阵的指数
exponential of a matrix if I see either
我想到的东西很久了
there's something I think of that long
无限系列给出了
infinite series that gives the
指数那些所有条款
exponential those all the terms in that
系列有一个这样的权力
series are have powers of a so
一切工作在每学期
everything is working every term in that
系列x是一个特征向量，当我
series x is an eigenvector and when I
这一切我都知道了
it all together I learned that the
特征值是e将拉姆达牛逼那
eigenvalue is e to the lambda T that's
只是一个典型而且成功的
just a typical and and and successful
工作用得好，所以我可以矢量
work use okay so that's I can vectors
和特征值，我们会发现一些
and eigen values and and we'll find some
现在在一分钟，所以我声称
in a minute now so I'm claiming that
从这开始就是这个
this is the this that from this first
就像某些事情一样
thing which was just like about certain
现在我们开始向量是特殊的
vectors are special now we're beginning
看看为什么他们这么有用
to see why there why they're useful so
特别是好的有用的甚至更好，所以
special is good useful is even better so
所以让我拿任何矢量说V和
so let me take take any vector say V and
没事做我想做的事情我想用什么
okay what do I want to do I want to use
特征向量这个V可能不是
eigen vectors this V is probably not an
本征向量，但我想我已经
eigen vector but I'm supposing that I've
得到了他们，我同意了
got n of them you and I are agreed that
也有一些矩阵对此有
there are some matrices for which there
不是一整套特征向量
are not a full set of eigen vectors
这真的是主要的
that's really the the main sort of
整个主题的讨厌点
annoying point in the whole subject of
线性代数，因为一些矩阵没有
linear algebra as some matrices don't
有足够的特征向量，但几乎所有
have enough eigenvectors but almost all
做，让我们继续前进，假设我们的
do and let's go forward assuming our
矩阵没关系，所以如果我有n
matrix has okay so if I've got n
作为基础的独立特征向量
independent eigenvectors that's a basis
我可以写任何矢量V作为
I can write any vector V as a
这些特征向量的组合是正确的
combination of those eigen vectors right
然后我就可以找到了什么
and then I can find out what a to the to
任何权力，所以这就是这一点
any power so that's the point that this
这将是简单的和
is this is going to be simple and and
为什么我们喜欢它的原因有我们喜欢
the reason why we like to have we like
知道特征向量，因为如果我
to know the eigen vectors because if I
选择
choose
作为我的基础向量V是一个组合
as my basis vectors V is a combination
现在，如果我乘以a或a
of them now if I multiply by a or a
然后是平方或者是K的功率
squared or a to the K power then it's
线性所以我可以将每个乘以a
linear so I can multiply each one by a
到了K，如果我繁殖，我会得到什么
to the K and what do I get if I multiply
那个家伙对K的力量还不错
that guy by a to the K power okay well
我只是要使用或者我在这里开始但是
I'm just gonna use or here I set in but
让我说K和我很抱歉我正在使用n
let me say K and I'm sorry I'm using n
对于矩阵的大小，所以我更好
for the size of the matrix so I better
在这里使用K作为典型案例
use K for the for the typical case here
所以我得到了什么
so what do I get
只是为了帮助我完成这个和
just to help me through this and and
我们很高兴哦，所以当我发生时会发生什么
we're happy oh so what happens when I
乘以a到K就是a
multiply that by a to the K it's an
当我乘以时，特征向量记得这样
eigenvector remember so when I multiply
通过a到KI获得c1，这只是一个
by a to the K I get c1 that's just a
数和a到K倍的特征
number and a to the K times that eigen
向量给lambda1到K倍
vector gives lambda 1 to the K times the
特征向量权利就是整点
eigenvector right that's the whole point
和线性说继续Cnlambda
and linearity says keep going C n lambda
n到K幂X，换句话说我
n to the K power X and in other words I
我可以服用，我可以申请任何权力
have I can take I can apply any power of
矩阵我可以应用指数
a matrix I can apply the exponential of
矩阵我可以快速做任何事情
a matrix I can do anything quickly
因为我已经得到了特征向量
because I've got the eigen vector so
真的，所以我说第一次使用
really so I'm saying the first use for
特征向量可能是主要用途
eigen vectors may be the principle use
他们被发明的是
for which they were invented is to be
能够如此解决差分方程
able to solve difference equations so so
如果我称之为VK，那就让我吧
this so let me if I call that VK the
案件权力然后是我正在解决的等式
case power then the equation I'm solving
这是一步差分方程
here is a one-step difference equation
这是我的差异方程，如果我
this is my difference equation and if I
想要使用指数的等式
wanted to use Exponential's the equation
我会被解决
I would be solving with
DVDT等于这些解决方案
DVD T equals a these solution to
离散步骤或连续时间
discrete steps or continuous time
如果我知道，进化是微不足道的
evolution comes is trivial if I know the
特征向量，因为这是解决方案
eigenvectors because here's the solution
这个和这个的解决方案
to this one and the solution to this one
是一回事C1e将拉姆达1吨
is the same thing c1 e to the lambda 1t
x1就是你所期望的
x1 is that what you were expecting for
这里的解决方案因为如果我
the for the solution here because if I
采取它带来的衍生物
take the derivative it brings down a
lambda如果我乘以它会降低
lambda if I multiply by a it brings down
lambda以及其他人还好吧
the lambda so plus the other guys okay
不是新闻，但要记住什么是重要的
not news but important to remember what
特征向量首先用于
eigenvectors are for in the first place
好啊，让我继续前进
good yeah let me move ahead
哦，一个矩阵
oh one one matrix
事实是关于类似的东西
fact is about something called similar
矩阵，所以我在我的矩阵上然后我
matrices so I have on my matrix a then I
了解它意味着什么
have the idea of what it means to be
类似于A所以B类似于a或
similar to a so B is similar to a or
是的，这意味着什么呢？
yeah what does that mean so here's
这就是它首先意味着什么
here's what it means first of all it
意味着B可以从中找到
means that B can be found from a by this
在按键操作这里乘以
is the key operation here multiplying by
矩阵M及其逆M逆am
a matrix M and its inverse M inverse am
当我看到两个矩阵B和A.
when I see two matrices B an A
通过那种方式连接起来的
that are connected by that kind of a
改变M可以是任何可逆矩阵
change M could be any invertible matrix
然后我会说是类似的一天
then I would say be with similar day and
那改变了那种外表
that changed that that that appearance
如果我改变，M很自然
of M is pretty natural if I change
这里的变量是M然后我得到了
variables here by M then I get that
类似的矩阵会显示出来的是什么
similar matrix will show up so what's
关键事实你还记得钥匙
the key fact do you remember the key
关于类似矩阵的事实，如果B和a
fact about similar matrices if B and a
连接一样，他们有
are connected like that they have the
相同的特征值所以这只是一个
same eigenvalues so this is a just a
有用的一点要记住，所以我会这
useful point to remember so I'll this is
就像在讨论中的一个事实
like one fact in the in the discussion
特征向量的等等
of eigenvalues and eigenvectors so
类似的矩阵具有相同的特征值
similar matrices same eigenvalues
是的，以某种方式在特征值
yeah so in in some way in the eigenvalue
特征向量世界他们就在这里
eigenvector world they're there in this
他们在一起，他们是
they belong together they they're
通过这种关系连接起来
connected by is by this relation that
结果证明是正确的事情
just turns out to be the right thing
实际上就是它给了我们一个线索
actually that is it gives us a clue of
如何实际计算特征值
how eigenvalues are actually computed
好吧，他们实际上是通过打字来计算的
well they're actually computed by typing
我用括号围绕着那个
I of a with parentheses around a that's
他们在现实生活中的表现如何
how they're in in real life but what
当你打字的时候我会给你一个好的
happens when you type I give a well you
可以说特征值出现在
could say the eigenvalue shows up on the
屏幕，但必须发生一些事情
screen but something had to happen in
那里
there
发生了什么事是MATLAB或
and what happened it was that MATLAB or
那个拿着那个矩阵的人开始使用了
whoever took that matrix a started using
M的很好的选择好你
good choices of M better and better you
知道采取了一堆步骤
know took a bunch of steps with
不同的M是因为如果我做另一个M.
different M's because if I do another M
如果我，我仍然有一个类似的矩阵
I still have a similar matrix right if I
如果我拿B并做一个不同的M2到B.
if I take B and do a different M 2 to B
所以我得到类似B，则事
so I get something similar to B then
这也和我的方式类似
that's also similar to way I've got a
那里有类似事物的全家人
whole family of similar things there and
它与MATLAB的作用是什么
what does it what does MATLAB do with
所有这些M和1和M2和M3和
all these M's and 1 and M 2 and M 3 and
所以它将矩阵带到三角形
so on it brings the matrix to triangular
矩阵
matrix
它得到了特征值
it gets the eigenvalues showing up on
对角线它非常棒
the diagonal it's just tremendously it
是那时的灵感
was the inspiration when that when there
当M的好选择出现时
when the good choice of M appeared and
我只想说，因为我要去上
let me just say because I'm going on to
对称矩阵，对称矩阵
symmetric matrices that for symmetric
矩阵一切都有点清洁
matrices everything is sort of cleaned
你不是不只是去
you're not you not only go to
三角形矩阵你朝着它去
triangular matrix you go to it toward a
对角矩阵它们让你厌烦
diagonal matrix they off tire you you
选择制作非对角线的M'
choose M's that make the off-diagonal
越来越小的东西
stuff smaller and smaller and smaller
并且特征值没有改变
and the eigenvalues are not changing so
他们在对角线上射击了
they're shooting up on the diagonal are
特征值，所以我想我应该
the eigenvalues so I guess I should
验证类似矩阵的事实
verify that fact that similar matrices
具有相同的特征值可以有
have the same eigen values can be there
不能表明我们不能太多
can't be much to show we can't be much
在证明中，因为这就是我所知道的
in the proof because that's all I know
我想知道它的特征值和
and I want to know its eigenvalues and
特征向量让我说假设m
eigenvectors so let me say suppose m
逆am具有特征向量Y和
inverse a m has the eigen vector Y and
本征值拉姆达，我想
the eigen value lambda and I want to
我想表明Y是一个
show do I want to show that Y is an
特征向量也是一个自己没有
eigen vector also of a itself no
特征向量正在改变我想做什么
eigenvectors are changing do I want to
表明中λ为的特征值
show that lambda is an eigenvalue of a
本身是的，这是我的观点所以我们可以看到
itself yes that's my point so can we see
那我可以看到lambda是一个
that huh can I see that lambda is an
特征值就像那里没有
eigenvalue there's like there's not a
我要做的很多，我的意思是，如果我不能这样做
lot to do here I mean if I can't do it
很快，我从来没有打算这样做，因为这样
soon I'm never going to do it because so
我该怎么办，是的，我可以
what am I going to do yeah I could yeah
X是我的关键，我可以
X is my is going to be a key and I can
当我看到M逆时，看到我的到来
see my coming just when I see M inverse
在那里或我将要做什么
over there or what am I going to do with
这件坏事我会把它放在上面
the darn thing I'm gonna put it on the
另一方面，我会倍增
other side I'm gonna multiply that
M的等式，所以我会有
equation by M so I'll have that we'll
把M放在这里，我会有一个My
put the M over here and I'll have a M y
等于lambda我的权利就是这样
equals lambda M Y right and is that
告诉我我想知道的是什么
telling me what I want to know yes
那是明智地说我的意思
that's saying that my that you wisely
建议给名字x2是lambda
suggested to given name x2 is lambda
我见到你了吗？
times my do you see that that
特征值lambda没有
that the eigen value lambda didn't
改变特征向量确实改变了它
change the eigenvector did change it
从Y改为我的那就是X了
changed from Y to my that's the X the
X的特征向量这是lambdaX是的
eigenvector of X this is lambda X yeah
所以这就是M的作用
so that's the role of M it just it just
给你一个不同的基础
gives you a different basis for
特征向量，但它不会改变
eigenvectors but it does not change
正确的价值是的，所以那些
eigen values right yeah okay so those
是类似的矩阵是的其他一些
are similar matrices yeah some other
好事发生在很多人身上
good things happened a lot of people
其实我不是很喜欢
don't know in fact I wasn't like very
意识到B时代的事实
conscious of the fact that a times B has
与B次相同的特征值
the same eigen values as B times a well
我是你也许我应该写下来
I'm you I should maybe write that down a
B具有相同的特征值
B has the same eigen values the same
非零，一旦你知道你会看到我有
nonzero once you know you'll see I have
两个作为这是任何a和B相同
two as be a this is any a and B same
大小我不是在说类似的矩阵
size I'm not talking similar matrices
这里我说的任何两个和B呀等等
here I'm talking any two a and B yeah so
这是现在发生的好事
that's a good thing that happens now
我们能不能看到一个，然后我就是
could we could we see one and then I'm
基本的，真的很开心
gonna be really pretty happy with basic
关于特征值的事实如此，如果我想要的话
facts about eigen values so so if I want
表明两两件事有相同
to show that two things have the same
特征值你的建议是什么
eigen values what what do you propose
表明他们已经相似了
show that they are similar I already
说如果它们相似，那么是否有M.
said if they're similar so is there an M
有没有M将连接这个
is there an M that will connect this
矩阵所以有一个M会
matrix so is there an M that will
乘这个矩阵方式，使
multiply this matrix that way so that
可能类似于B而且我可以
would be similar to a B and can I
然后产生B.
produce B a then
所以我只想把这个词放在这里我
so I'll just put the word want up here I
我想，如果我有，那我就完成了
want if I if I have that then I'm done
因为那就是那两个
because that's saying that those two
矩阵B和BA是相似的，我
matrices a B and BA are similar and I
知道那时候他们也一样
know that then they have the same
特征值所以它们应该是mbm
eigenvalues so are they what should mb m
应该是这样，我想要的是什么
should be so what does I am here I want
这是真的应该是我是一个人
that to be true should mb be yeah a me
男孩不是最隐蔽的事实
will be boy not the most hidden fact
拿这个取m等于B然后我就B了
here take take m equal B so then I've B
次次BB逆这是
times a times B B inverse which is the
身份所以我有B时间说是的好
identity so I have B time say yes okay
所以b-and-ba很好没有做什么
so so a b-and-b a are fine no what do
你想到这个问题是
you think about this question are the
特征行我现在知道一个B＆Ba
eigen rows I now know that a B & B a of
相同的特征值和原因我
the same eigen values and the reason I
不得不小心非零
had to be careful about non zero is that
如果我的特征值为零，那我就是我
if I had zero eigen values then yeah I I
不能指望那些逆转的权利
can't count on those inverses right
对，所以这就是我投入的原因
right so so that's why I put in that
小资格赛，但现在我想问
little qualifier but now I want to ask
这个问题，如果我知道特征值
this question if I know the eigenvalues
现在分别由a和B分开
of a separately by itself a and of B now
我正在谈论任何两个矩阵a和
I'm talking about any two matrices a and
B如果我有两个矩阵a和我有
B if if I have two matrices a and I have
矩阵A和矩阵B，我知道
a matrix a and a matrix B and I know
那些是我可以在他们的价值观
those are I can values in their
特征值B一次B可以怎么样
eigenvalues what about a B a times B can
我乘以时间的特征值
I multiply the eigenvalues of a time's
b的特征值
the eigenvalues of b
不要做对了是对的特征值
don't do it right yes right eigen values
一次B的特征值可以
of a times the eigen values of B could
什么都不对，他们不是
be damn near anything right they're not
连接到B的特征值
connected to the eigen values of a B
特别是在某些东西可能
especially in maybe some something could
被发现但不是很多，同样如此
be discovered but not much and similarly
为了加号B，所以是的，所以让我
for a plus B that so yeah so so let me
只记下这一点，我给出了价值观
just write down this point I give values
加B的一般不是本征的
of a plus B are generally not eigen
中的值再加上我的价值观
values of a plus I in values of be
通常不只是没有理由和
generally not just there's no reason and
他们是我得到的原因
they're the reason that that's I get
没有答案是特征向量可以
that no answer is the eigen vectors can
是所有不同的，如果特征向量
be all different if the eigen vectors
对于一个完全不同的
for a are totally different from the
B的本征向量然后加上B将
eigen vectors for B then a plus B will
可能还有其他一些
have probably some other totally
不同的特征向量和那里
different eigen vectors and there's
没有什么事情发生在那里
nothing nothing happening there there's
关于本征的那种想法
that sort of a thoughts about eigen
总的来说，我可以有一个
values in general and I could there be a
关于特征向量的整个部分，但我是
whole section on eigen vectors but I'm
对...的特征向量真正感兴趣
really interested in eigenvectors of
对称矩阵所以我要移动
symmetric matrices so I'm going to move
关于这个话题所以现在已经谈过了
on to that topic so now having talked
关于我要专攻的任何矩阵
about any matrix a I'm gonna specialize
对称矩阵看看有什么特别之处
to symmetric matrices see what's special
关于特征值是什么的
about the eigenvalues are there what's
特别关于那里的特征向量
special about the eigenvectors there and
我想我们已经在课堂上说过了
i think we've already said it in class
所以让我让我问你告诉我
so let me let me ask you to tell me
关于它再次告诉我所以我会打电话给你
about it tell me again so I'll call that
矩阵现在总是提醒你
matrix s now as a reminder always that
我在这里谈论对称性
I'm talking here about symmetric
矩阵那么我的关键是什么
matrices so what do i what are the key
事实要知道我的价值观是真实的
facts to know I can values are real
如果矩阵是我的实数
real numbers if the matrix is I'm
关于实对称矩阵的思考
thinking of real symmetric matrices of
当然其他真正的矩阵可能有
course other real matrices could have
虚构的特征值其他真正的主要
imaginary eigenvalues other real major
所以，让我们想一下
so just let's just think for a moment
是的，也许我会把它放在这里，我可以
yeah maybe I'll just put it here can I
在我继续前进之前回来
back up before I keep going with
对称矩阵所以采用矩阵
symmetric matrices so so take a matrix
赞赞赞是Q是啊，这将是
like like like that Q yeah that would be
一个Q，但它不是特别是Q也许是
a Q but it's not specially a Q maybe the
也许是最引人注目的事情
maybe the most remarkable thing about
那个矩阵是反对称的
that matrix is that it's anti-symmetric
如果我，我会称之为正确
so I'll call it a for right if I
转置那个矩阵我得到了什么
transpose that matrix what do I get
负面因此就像反对
there negative so that's like anti
对称，我声称反对
symmetric and I claim that an anti
对称矩阵具有虚构
symmetric matrix has imaginary
特征值，这就是那个
eigenvalues so that's a that's a that's
你可能会说90度旋转
a 90 degree rotation and you might say
有什么能比这更简单的90
what could be simpler than that a 90
学位轮换并不奇怪
degree rotation that's not a weird
矩阵，但从的角度来看
matrix but from the point of view of
特征向量有些奇怪的东西
eigenvectors some things little odd has
发生在正确，因为如果我有一个90
to happen right because if I have a 90
如果我采用矢量X任何一个程度旋转
degree rotation if I take a vector X any
矢量X它可能是一个
vector X could it possibly be an
特征向量很好地适用于你
eigenvector well apply a to it you'd be
朝这个方向走了一个X而且有
off in this direction a X and there is
没有办法，一个X可以是X的倍数
no way that a X can be a multiple of X
所以有这个问题并没有真正的特征向量
so there's no real eigenvector for that
对于那个反对称矩阵或任何
for that anti-symmetric matrix or any
反对称矩阵是的，所以你看
anti symmetric matrix yep so you see
当我们说的是特征值时
that when we say that the eigenvalues of
我们说的是对称矩阵
a symmetric matrix are real we're saying
这可能不会发生这
that this couldn't happen that this
如果它们是对称的，就不可能发生
couldn't happen if they were symmetric
在这里它是一个非常相反的
and here it's a very opposite it's
反对称井即好
antisymmetric well well that's on the
董事会你可能会说等一下如何
board you might say wait a minute how
可能有任何特征向量
could that have any eigenvector
什么是什么是特征向量
whatsoever so what is an eigenvector of
那个矩阵你怎么找到的
that matrix a how do you find the
当它们是两个时的特征向量
eigenvectors of a when they're two by
这是我们知道如何计算的两个
two that's a calculation we know how to
你还记得那里的那些台阶吗？
do you remember the steps there I'm
寻找斧头等于lambdaX如此正确
looking for ax equal lambda X so right
现在我正在寻找两个lambda附件
now I'm looking for both lambda annex
我有两个
I've got two
这不是线性的，但我会带来的
that's not linear but I'm gonna bring
这个到了这一边并写成一个
this over to this side and write it as a
减去lambdaIX等于零然后
minus lambda I X equal to zero and then
我在那得看和说哇
I'm gonna look at that and say wow a
减去lambda我必须是不可逆的
minus lambda I must be not invertible
因为它的空值为X.
because it's got this X in its null
空间因此决定了这个矩阵
space so the determinant of this matrix
必须为零我不能为空
must be zero I couldn't have a null
空间，这是决定因素是零
space and that's the determinant is zero
然后当我看一个减去lambda我
and then when I look at a minus lambda I
对于这个我有减去lambdas-嘿
for this a I've got minus lambdas - hey
哦，它只是一个，那是减一
oh it's just a one and that's minus one
我要采取决定因素和什么
I'm gonna take the determinant and what
我是否会选择决定因素
am I going to get for the determinant
lambda平方加一，我设定了
lambda squared plus one and I set that
为零
to zero
所以我只是遵循所有规则但是
so I'm just following all the rules but
它向我展示了lambda这两个
it's showing me that the lambda the two
lambdas这里有两个lambdas但是
lambdas there are two lambdas here but
他们不是真的，因为那个等式
they're not real because that equation
根源是我和减去我所以那些
the roots are I and minus I so those are
特征值，它们很好
the eigenvalues and they have the nice
他们一切都很好
they have all the well they are the
特征值毫无疑问与
eigenvalues no doubt about it with
两个两个快速检查
two-by-two there are two quick checks
告诉你是的你做了
that tell you yeah you did the
如果我添加了两种计算权
calculation right if I add up the two
如果我把这两个加起来，那么这个特征值
eigenvalues in this if I add up the two
任何矩阵的特征值，我要去
eigenvalues for any matrix and I'm going
为这个做这件事，我得到了答案
to do it for this one I get what answer
我从添加中得到了相同的答案
I get the same answer from the adding
添加lambdas给我的添加
add the add the lambdas gives me the
添加对角线的答案相同
same answer as add the diagonal of the
如果我添加，我正在调用的矩阵
matrix which I'm calling a so if I add
对角线我得零和零所以它是
the diagonal I get zero and zero so it's
零加零和这个数字加
zero plus zero and this number adding
对角线称为迹线和
the diagonal is called the trace and
我们会再次看到它，因为它就是这样
we'll see it again because it's so
简单只需添加对角线项
simple just adding the diagonal entries
在什么时候给你一些关键信息
gives you a key bit of information when
你加下来对角线它告诉你
you add down the diagonal it tells you
本征值拉姆达的总和它
the sum of the eigen value lambda it
不会分别告诉你每个lambda
doesn't tell you each lambda separately
但它会告诉你总和所以它会告诉你
but it tells you the sum so it tells you
通过做一件事情啊这么一个事实
one fact by doing one thing yeah so
这非常方便，给你一个快速
that's pretty handy gives you a quick
检查，如果你知道你的自行车，当你
check if you've you know bike when you
计算这个决定因素并求解
compute this determinant and solve for
拉姆达
lambda
你这是一种计算方式
the thing you this is a way to compute
手工特征值你可以做一个
eigenvalues by hand you could make a
错误，因为它是二次方程式
mistake because it's a quadratic formula
对于2x2，但您可以通过添加
for 2x2 but you can check by adding the
两个根你得到的相同吗？
two roots do you get the same as the
跟踪0加0，还有另外一个
trace 0 plus 0 well there's one other
同样快速检查2乘222
check equally quick for 2 by 2 so 2 by 2
你是真的让他们正确的是什么
is you really get them right what's the
其他检查2我们添加我们的特征值
other check 2 we add the eigen values we
得到我们乘以特征的轨迹
get the trace we multiply the eigen
价值所以我们现在这样做，所以我会
values so we take so so now I'll
乘以lambdas然后我得到我
multiply the lambdas so then I get I
时间减去我和那应该相等
times minus I and that should equal
让我们看看它应该是什么
let's don't look yet what should it
如果我乘以特征值I则相等
equal if I multiply the eigen values I
应该得到一个决定权
should get the determinant right of a so
这2个方便的检查添加了本征
that's 2 handy checks add the eigen
任何尺寸3乘以34乘4的值但是
values for any size 3 by 3 4 by 4 but
这只是2次检查
it's only 2 checks
所以42比2它是你得到它的那种3
so 4 2 by 2 it's kind of you got it 3 by
34比4你仍然可以做到
3 4 by 4 you could still have made an
错误和两个检查可以
error and the two checks could
可能仍然工作让我们检查一下
potentially still work let's just check
它在这里是什么，我减去我1
it out here what's I times minus I 1
因为它是负的我平方而且那是
because it's minus I squared and that's
加上1和它的决定因素
plus 1 and the determinant of that
矩阵是0减去1是的
matrix is 0 minus is 1 yep
好的，所以我们得到了一个好的，真的
ok so we got one good those are really
关于特征值，但关键事实
the key facts about eigenvalues but of
当然，他们不是不是
course the they're not it's not as
简单的解决斧头等于B找到
simple as solving ax equal B to find
他们，但如果你跟随它
them but it's if you follow
关于类似矩阵的概念和
on this idea of similar matrices and
那种砍下非对角线
sort of chopped down the off-diagonal
部分然后确定特征值
part then sure enough the eigenvalues
好好表现出来
got to show up okay
对称对称矩阵现在好了
symmetric symmetric matrices okay so now
我们将具有对称性然后
we're going to have symmetric and then
我们的特殊性甚至比
we'll have the special even better than
对称是对称的正定
symmetric is symmetric positive-definite
好吧对称你告诉我主要的
okay symmetric you told me the main
事实是特征值真实的本征
facts are the eigenvalues real the eigen
矢量正交，我猜其实
vectors orthogonal and I guess actually
是的所以我想把这个拿走
yeah so I want to put the take to put
那些成为数学符号而不是单词
those into math symbols instead of words
所以是的，我猜是的，我只是
so yeah yeah I guess yeah shall I just
跳进去，隐藏另一件事
jump in and the other other thing hidden
那里但是非常重要的是有
there but but very important is there's
一套完整的特征向量，即使有些
a full set of eigenvectors even if some
特征值碰巧被重复像
eigenvalues happen to be repeated like
身份矩阵仍然充足
the identity matrix it still got plenty
特征向量，这是一个附加点
of eigenvectors so that's an added point
我不是在那里制造的，我会尽我所能
that I'm not made there and I'll I could
证明这两个陈述，但为什么不
prove those two statements but why don't
我请你接受它们并继续前进
I ask you to accept them and go onward
我们该怎么跟他们没关系和
what are we gonna do with them okay and
是啊
yeah
好吧，你能不能让我们拥有一个
okay can you just like let's have an
例如刚起来让我把一个例子
example just up let me put an example
这里假设非调用它是零
here suppose s non calling it s is zeros
1＆1这样它的对称性是什么
1 & 1 so that's symmetric what are its
特征值是什么特征值
eigenvalues what are the eigenvalues of
对称矩阵的正负1
that symmetric matrix s plus and minus 1
那么，如果你打算特征值我会
well if you propose to eigenvalues I'll
把它们写下来1和减去1然后
write them down 1 and minus 1 and then
我该怎么做才能检查它们的痕迹和
what will I do to check them trace and
决定性的确定他们是或是真的
determinant ok so are they or is it true
特征值为1和-1
that the eigenvalues are 1 and minus 1
好吧，我如何检查跟踪是什么
okay how do I check the trace what is
那个矩阵0的痕迹和什么的
the trace of that matrix 0 and what's
特征值的总和0好什么
the sum of the eigenvalues 0 good what
关于确定什么是决定因素
about determinate what's the determinant
s减1的乘积
of s minus 1 the product of the
特征值减1，所以我们已经没事了
eigenvalues minus 1 so we've got it ok
哪些特征向量是什么向量
what are the eigenvectors what vector
你可以乘以它而不是它
can you multiply by and it doesn't
改变方向实际上并没有改变
change direction in fact doesn't change
我正在寻找特征向量
at all i'm looking for the eigenvector
这是一个稳定的状态01
that's a steady state 0 1
我认为这是11是的所以这里是
I think it's 1 1 yeah so here's the
lambda表达式，然后特征向量是我
lambdas and then the eigenvectors are I
认为11是正确的，是的，确定SS是
think 1 1 is that right yeah sure SS is
这只是一种排列而已
just a permutation here it's just
交换这两个条目以便一对一交换
exchanging the two entries so one on one
不会改变，另一个是什么
won't change and what what's the other
特征向量1和负1
eigenvector 1 and minus 1
然后我在想着记住
and then I'm thinking remembering about
我认为这是类似的东西
this similar stuff I'm thinking that a s
类似于刚刚显示的矩阵
is similar to a matrix that just shows
特征值所以s类似于我
the eigenvalues so s is similar to I'm
我要去M井
going to put in an M well I'm going to
用那个矩阵连接那个矩阵
connect s that matrix with the
具有的特征值矩阵
eigenvalue matrix which has the
特征值所以这里是我的每个人的电话
eigenvalues so here's my everybody calls
矩阵资本lambda因为
that matrix capital lambda because
每个人都很少调用特征值
everybody calls the eigenvalues little
lambda所以有它们的矩阵是
lambda so the matrix that has them is
叫做资本lambda，我的主张是
called capital lambda and I my claim is
这些家伙是相似的，这
that these guys are similar that this
你在那里看到的矩阵我
matrix s that you're seeing up there I
相信有一个MI相信有
believe there's an M I believe there's
一个M所以我在这里放了什么呢
an M so that s what did I put in here so
我下面的这个模式，我相信
I'm following this pattern I believe
会有M和M
that there would be an M and an M
反使这将意味着，和
inverse so that this would mean that and
这首先很好，就是这样
that's nice first of all it's it would
确认特征值保持不变
confirm that the eigenvalues stay the
这其中这是一定相同
same which which which was certain to
发生，然后它也意味着
happen and then it would also mean that
我曾经有一个对角矩阵和
I had got a diagonal matrix and of
当然，这是一个自然的目标
course that's a natural goal to get a
对角矩阵所以我们可能希望如此
diagonal matrix so we might hope that
让我们到达那里的M就像一个
the M that gets us there is like an
重要的矩阵所以你看到我是什么
important matrix so do you see what I'm
在这里做它是在标题下
doing here it comes under the heading of
对角化矩阵我从一开始
diagonalizing a matrix I start with a
矩阵s我发现它们的特征值
matrix s I find its eigenvalues they go
进入lambda，我相信我能找到
on into lambda and I believe I can find
一个M，所以我看到他们是相似的
an M so that I see there they're similar
它们具有相同的特征值1和-1
they have the same eigen values 1 and -1
双方都是如此
both sides so only
在的问题是什么在什么是
in question is what's in what's the
矩阵，对角化了所拥有的东西
matrix that diagonalizes s the what have
我们离开了使用特征向量
we got left to use the eigenvectors the
矩阵，所以我可以把M喜欢
matrix that so can I put the M like over
是的，我会把那个余烬逆
there yeah I'll put that ember inverse
我要去另一边哦
is going to go over to the other side oh
它在这里并不涉及我们
it goes here doesn't involve us I was
我担心那里看起来不太好看
like worried there I didn't look good
但是，所以这一切都将成为现实
but yeah so so this is all going to be
权利，如果这是不是想我来
right if if this is what I'd like to
SIm等于mlambdasm等于m
have SI m equal m lambda s m equal m
拉姆达
lambda
那是对齐矩阵的
that's diagonalizing a matrix that's
使用特征向量找到m
finding the m using the eigenvectors
产生类似的矩阵λ
that produces a similar matrix lambda
其中有一个是这样的特征值
which has the eigenvalues that that's
这是关于的重要事实
that's the great fact about
对角化就是你如何使用它
diagonalizing that's how you use that's
另一种说法是这样的
another way to say this is how the
特征向量可以让你付出代价
eigenvectors pay off you put them into m
你采取类似的矩阵，它
you take the similar matrix and it's
很好，对角线，你看到了吗？
nice and diagonal and do you see that
这将发生在时间，所以M有
this will happen s time so M has the
第一特征向量和第二特征向量
first eigen vector and the second eigen
矢量，我相信第一个
vector and I believe that the first
特征向量x结束时的第二个
eigenvector x the second at end the
第二个特征向量再次出现
second eigenvector that's am again on
这边没有我只是写在100
this side no me just write in the 1 0 0
减1我相信这就好了
minus 1 I believe this got to be like
确认我们已经完成了他们的事情
confirming that we've done their thing
正确确认特征向量
right confirming that the eigen vectors
在这里工作可以就像请做
work here could just like please make
当你看到时，从最后一行感觉到
sense out of that last line when you see
最后一行我的意思是什么
that last line how what do I mean to
理解我想看到的东西
make sense out of it what I want to see
这是真的，我怎么看
that that's true how do I see that
我怎么做这样左边的是什么
how do I do this so what's the left side
什么是正确的一面，如果是的话
and what's the right side so what if if
我将s乘以几列
I multiply s by a couple of columns
答案是什么
what's the answer
SX1和sx2是美的
SX 1 and s x2 that's the beauty of
矩阵乘法，如果我乘以a
matrix multiplication if I multiply a
矩阵由另一个矩阵我可以做到
matrix by another matrix I can do it a
列一次有四个
column at a time there there are four
这样就可以很好地增加矩阵
great ways to multiply matrices so this
另一个是一次一个一列，以便
is another one a column at a time so
这个左手边是SX1
this left hand side is SX 1
SX-我只是做每一栏和什么
SX - I just do each column and what
关于右手边我可以做到这一点
about the right hand side I can do that
乘法X1减去X2
multiplication X 1 minus X 2 did
有人说死不，我不想要哦
somebody say death no I don't want oh
借口编正确确定，当你说未来
excuse ed it right ok when you say next
1减X2我减去了你
1 minus X 2 I was subtracting but you
这意味着第一列是X.
meant that that's the first column is X
1和第二列是负X2
1 and the second column is minus X 2
纠正我们对此深感抱歉，做我们来
correct sorry about that and did we come
是的，因为现在我比较了SX1
out right yes because now I compare SX 1
是lambda1X1sX2是lambda2X2和
is lambda 1 X 1s X 2 is lambda 2 X 2 and
我是金色的，所以重点是什么
I'm golden so what was the point of this
我们学到了什么，我们学得很好
board what did we learn we learned well
我们有点期待原来的
we kind of expected that the original s
就像lambda一样
would be similar to the lambdas because
特征值匹配s具有本征
the eigen values match s has eigen
值lambda和这个对角矩阵
values lambda and this diagonal matrix
肯定有1和-1的特征值
certainly has eigen values 1 and minus 1
特征值的对角矩阵
a diagonal matrix the eigen values are
在你面前，所以他们是相似的
right in front of you so they're similar
s类似于lambda和那里
s is similar to the lambda and there
应该是M然后是某人
should be an M and then somebody
建议也许M是
suggested maybe the M is the
特征向量，这是正确的答案
eigenvectors and that's the right answer
所以最后让我写下来
so finally let me write that
在这里不仅仅是对称的
in here which isn't just for symmetric
所以也许我应该把它放在矩阵中
so maybe I should put it for matrix a so
如果它有lambdas和eigenvectors和
if it has lambdas and eigenvectors and
该要求是：时间是在
the claim is that a time's the
特征向量矩阵是特征向量
eigenvector matrix is the eigenvector
矩阵乘以特征值，我会
matrix times the eigenvalues and i would
缩短到ax等于xlambda和
shorten that to a x equals x lambda and
我可以重写那个然后我会慢下来
i could rewrite that and then i'll slow
向下作为相等的xlambdaX逆
down as a equal x lambda X inverse
真的，这是把它们整合在一起
really this is bringing it all together
这是一个简单的小公式
in a simple small formula it's telling
我们a类似于lambda它
us that a is similar to lambda it's
告诉我们做的矩阵M.
telling us the matrix M that does the
作为它的特征向量和矩阵
job it's the matrix of eigenvectors and
所以这就像写作的简写方式
so it's like a shorthand way to write
什么权利有关的主要事实
what right the main facts about
特征值和特征向量怎么样
eigenvalues and eigenvectors what about
我可以回到原点
a squared can I go back to the very
第一个IC时间接近这里结束
first IC time as close to the end here
什么是平方是什么
what about a squared what are the
什么是平方的特征向量
eigenvectors of a squared what are the
平方的特征值就像是
eigenvalues of a squared that's like the
特征值的整点或我
whole point of eigenvalues well or I
可以把那个愚蠢的东西放到X上
could just square that stupid thing X
lambdaX逆XlambdaX逆和
lambda X inverse X lambda X inverse and
我有什么X逆X在
what have I got X inverse X in the
中间是身份所以我有Xlambda
middle is identity so I have X lambda
平方X反向和我的那个
squared X inverse and to me that unto
你说的
you that says
项目值已经平方
the item values have been squared the
特征向量没有改变是的，没关系
eigenvectors didn't change yeah okay and
现在最后一口气是如果的话
now finally last breath is what if the
矩阵是对称的然后我们有
matrix is symmetric then we have
不同的字母，这是唯一的
different letters that's the only that's
特征向量的显着变化
a significant change the eigenvector
矩阵现在是一个正交矩阵我
matrix is now an orthogonal matrix I'm
回到关键的事实
coming back to the key facts of what
使对称如何阅读如何
makes symmetric how do I read how do I
看到对称帮助我的本征
see symmetric helping me in the eigen
矢量和特征值世界很好
vector and eigen value world well it
告诉我，特征向量
tells me that the eigenvectors are
正交所以X是Q的特征值
orthogonal so the X is Q the eigenvalues
是真实的，特征向量是x
are real and the eigenvectors is x
逆，但现在我要做那些
inverse but now I'm going to make those
特征向量和单位向量我要去
eigenvectors and unit vectors I'm going
为了规范它，所以我真的允许我
to normalize it so I'm really allowing I
有一个正交矩阵Q所以我有一个
have an orthogonal matrix Q so I have a
写这个的不同方式就是这样
different way to write this and this is
今天的课程Qlambda结束了
the end of the today's class Q lambda
什么是你能告诉我关于Q的事情
and what's what can you tell me about Q
逆它的Q转感谢使
inverse it's Q transpose thanks so that
这是现在的最后一次演讲
was the last lecture so now the
正交演讲将在即将到来
orthogonal lecture is coming up at the
对称矩阵的最后一秒
last second of the symmetric matrices
讲座，这个名字是谱
lecture and this has the name spectral
我刚刚放在那里和整个的定理
theorem which I just put there and whole
重点是，它告诉你每一个
point is that it tells you what every
symmetric matrix looks like orthogonal
对称矩阵看起来像正交
特征向量实特征值
eigenvectors real eigenvalues